Guide to the Robert W. Kirk papers, 1946-2004
Kirk, Robert W. papers, 1946-2004
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert W. Kirk papers, 1946-2004
24-02-3372
Kirk, Robert Warren, 1922-
0.9 cubic ft
Correspondence, photographs, video cassettes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, photographs, video cassettes related to Dr. Robert W. Kirk's career in veterinary medicine.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Dr. Robert W. Kirk was born May 20, 1922 in Stamford, Connecticut. He received his B.S. from the University of Connecticut in 1943, and his DVM from Cornell University in 1946. He married Helen M. Grandish in 1949 and they have three children.
Dr. Kirk's work in companion animal medicine is internationally recognized. He is perhaps best known for his text, Current Veterinary Therapy, currently in its 13th edition.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, photographs, video cassettes related to Dr. Robert W. Kirk's career in veterinary medicine, including his writings as well as his work at the Cornell University Hospital for Animals at the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kirk, Robert Warren, 1922-; Cornell University. Hospital for Animals; Cornell University. College of Veterinary Medicine.
Subjects:
Veterinary medicine -- Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Videocassettes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
Donated by Dr. Robert Kirk in 2004.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biography
  - General, 1946-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - News Clippings, 1967-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards, 1978-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Certificates (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - General, 1949-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General, 1996-2000, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Guyana, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Italy, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Japan, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Seeing Eye, Inc., 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - South Africa, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series III. Writings
  - Current Veterinary Therapy, 1974-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - First Aid for Pets, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Handbook of Veterinary Procedures and Emergency Treatment, 1985, 1990, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Small Animal Dermatology, 1983, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Small Animal Medicine: Past, Present and Future, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Portraits, 1959-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Personal, 1966-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, 1973-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Retirement Reception, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Kirk with "Meg", ca. 1970s (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dean Hagan with Christmas Letters, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series V. Miscellaneous
  - Cornell University Small Animal Clinic, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Japan/Australia Sabbatic, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jack Mara Awards - videos, 1997, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 16)